Zhi Qi Lee

Mobile: +44(0)7926959908 | email: zgbinbin8@gmail.com Linkedin: www.linkedin.com/in/zhiqi-lee/ | Github: github.com/abc12345d

Profile

As a software engineer with 6+ years of coding experience, my aim has been to explore different parts of computer science, thereby acquiring hands-on experience. With exposure to a wide array of technologies across multiple programming languages and frameworks, I am confident that I will be able to pick up new skills and technologies quickly. Please check out my personal website (https://zglee.xvz) where I take notes and showcase projects.

Education

The University of Edinburgh

Sep. 2018 - Nov. 2022

BSc (Hons) Artificial Intelligence and Computer Science (1st)

Edinburgh, United Kingdom

• Relevant modules: Computational Logic, Functional Programming, Object-Oriented Programming, Software Engineering, Computer Systems, Algorithms and Data Structures, Applied Machine Learning, Database Systems, Text Technologies for Data Science, Computer Architecture

Sunway College Johor Bahru

Jan. 2016 - Jun. 2017 Johor Bahru, Malaysia

Cambridge International A' Level

 Computer Science (A), Mathematics (A), Accounting (A), Economics (A) Outstanding Cambridge Learner Awards 2017 for Computer Science (Highest marks in Malaysia)

Projects

Personal Website | React.js, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Jul. 2023 - Aug. 2023

- Designed and built portfolio website from scratch with Vite
- Implemented dynamic routing with React Router, leading to a reduction in initial load time
- Deployed the website on Github Pages
- Developed an automated CI/CD pipeline with Github Actions to build and deploy, resulting in a 70% reduction in deployment time

Computational Psychiatry in PTSD | Python, PyMC3, Theano

Sep. 2021 - Sep. 2022

Honour project https://github.com/abc12345d/Honour-Project

- Critical analysis and compared all the algorithmic models of PTSD
- Implemented the Rescorla-Wagner (RW) model from scratch
- Runs parameter recovery using hierarchical Bayesian model and Markov chain Monte Carlo (MCMC) sampling algorithm

Mini database system | Java

Mar. 2022 - Apr. 2022

A relational database system which handles conjunctive queries (subset of SQL)

- Implemented basic data operations such as scanning, selection, projection, join and aggregation and relational operators by using OOP concepts
- Built query tree and database engine which handles queries according to query tree
- Optimised database performance by query minimisation and query plan transformation, resulting in at least a 75% reduction in query processing time
- Scored 90 for this coursework where the maximum score is 100 and the average score is 64.6

Gutenberg Book Search Website | Python, MongoDB, PyMongo

Jan. 2022 - Mar. 2022

- Worked in a group of 6, and collaborated using Trello, Teams and Github
- Cleaned data scraped from the Project Gutenberg website
- Performed data preprocessing in preparation for the search engine implementation.
- · Responsible for work related to databases, such as the design of database schema, setup and maintenance of the database and implementation of the database accessor module

Drone path planning program | Maven, Java

A medium-scale path planning software

https://abc12345d.github.io/file_server/ilp_report.pdf

- Analysed project requirements and developed the software architecture by applying OOP concepts and Effective Java concepts such as immutability
- Demonstrated the software architecture with UML class diagrams
- Wrote Javadoc to generate API documentation from Java source codes
- Scored 90 for this coursework where the average score is 74.64 and the maximum score is 100

Working Experiences

Tutor & Marker

Sep. 2019 - Dec. 2020

Oct. 2020 - Dec. 2020

School of Informatics, University of Edinburgh

Edinburgh, United Kingdom

- Worked as a teaching support team member for the Introduction to Computation course with over 450 students
- Prepared for tutorials and helped students in understanding the key concepts of course during tutorial sessions

Marked formal assessments and provided constructive feedback

Lab Demonstrator

Sep. 2019 - Dec. 2019

School of Informatics, University of Edinburgh

Edinburgh, United Kingdom

- Assisted students in configuring their programming environments
- Explained coding problems with examples
- Provided guidance to students as they worked through lab exercises.

Sales Team Leader

Sep. 2017 - Jun. 2018

Oh Honey Enterprise

Johor Bahru, Malaysia

- Top seller in the team since the third month of doing this job and record maintained throughout the whole period
- Formulated new sales strategies, resulting in an 80% increase in revenue
- Built and promoted long-lasting customer relationships
- Organised trade show booth, including layout, set up and disassembling of equipment
- Trained junior sales staff

Extra-Curricular Experiences

Volunteer

Jul. 2021 – Feb. 2022

The Turing Trust

Edinburgh, United Kingdom

- Tested the functionality of computers
- Wiped and refurbished computers

Technical Skills

Programming Languages: Python, Java, JavaScript, HTML/CSS, SQL, Dart, Haskell, C++

Technologies: React, PyTorch, Pandas, NumPy, Scikit-Learn, Matplotlib, BeautifulSoup, Selenium, Tkinter, Flutter

Database: PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Developer Tools: Git, Linux CLI, VS Code, npm, Conda, Vim, Markdown, LaTeX